Previously on 'Prison Break'
'Prison Break' 지난 줄거리
I'm breaking out,
전 탈옥을 할 겁니다
and you're going to make sure
my brother goes with me.
소장님께서는 제 형도 함께
갈 수 있도록 해주실 테고요
I'm sorry, Henry.
죄송해요, 소장님
This message is for Maricruz.
마리크루즈에게 남기는 내용이에요
I'll be there
거기 있을게
in the airport,
in Ixtapa waiting for you.
익스타파 공항에서
자기를 기다리고 있을게
Sucre, down the road, if you're in trouble,
post a note on the message board.
수크레, 나중에 문제가 생기면
게시판에 글을 남겨
- What's it called?
- Europeangoldfinch.net
- 어디다 남기라고?
That's a bird, right?
새 이름이잖아, 맞지?
Go pack your things.
We're moving.
나갈테니 가서 짐 싸
We will be a family , if it kills us.
우린 가족이 될거야
죽는 한이 있어도 말야
Pull this off and
you're halfway home.
이 일만 해내고 나면
가족들에게 갈 수 있잖아요
You remember what home is like?
Don't you?
집이 어떻게 생겼는지 기억하지요?
Stay away from my family!
내 가족에겐 얼씬도 하지마!
She needs that medicine.
그 약을 먹어야 해요
She can't go two days without it.
그거없인 이틀도
못 버틴단 말이에요
- I don't feel good.
- Oh, sweetie..
- 나 속이 이상해, 아빠
- 오, 얘야
Michael, I want for this to be over.
마이클, 제발 이상황이
끝났으면 좋겠어요
That makes two of us.
저도 마찬가지에요
It's just a question of looking at
whatever it is your father gave you.
아버지께서 주신게 무엇이든
그걸 알아내는 것이 문제에요
It's just a key.
그냥 열쇠에요
It's locked in a box
inside that cigar club.
저 시가 클럽 안에 있는
상자에 감추어져 있어
I'm not a wanted fugitive.
Give me the key. I'll do it.
난 수배자가 아니니까
내가 할게. 열쇠를 줘
You want to take a walk?
바람 좀 쐴까요?
싱크제작 / 한글번역 - 김선광
(audisaya@nate.com)
자막배포 - 네이트 드라마 24 자유제작
(http://club.nate.com/24)
자유배포 / 수정금지
배포시 제작자 정보를 꼭 밝혀주세요
Miss Tancredi?
텐크레디 양?
I need to have a word with you.
잠시 얘기 좀 하시지요
- Miss Tancredi?
- Of course.
- 텐크레디 양?
- 그러시죠
Miss Tancredi?
Ma'am?
텐크레디 양?
손님?
Miss Tancredi?
텐크레디 양?
It's time to go.
나가야겠어요
Ma'am?
손님?
They're going out the back.
뒷문으로 나가려한다
Come on! come on!
갑시다! 가요!
미네소타 주(州), 미니애폴리스
미니애폴리스/세인트 폴 국제공항
Pediatrics, please.
소아과 부탁합니다
콜로라도 주(州), 두랑고
Hello.
여보세요?
콜로라도 주(州), 두랑고
Cameron.
캐머론
콜로라도 주(州), 두랑고
Hi, Dad.
아빠, 안녕
- How are you doing, big guy?
- 요녀석, 어떻게 지내니?
- Good. I'm eating my lunch.
- 잘 지내죠. 점심먹고 있어요
- How is it?
- Pretty disgusting.
- 맛있니?
- 무진장 맛없어요
Maybe your mom can bring you
some dinner from home.
엄마한테 저녁은 집에서
만들어오라고 해야겠구나
- Did you see the doctor today?
- 오늘 의사선생님이 보고가셨니?
- Yeah.
- 네
He said I can go home this week
as long as I stay out of the street.
의사선생님이 밖에 안나간다 약속하면
이번주에 집에 갈 수 있다고 하셨어요
You're a smart young man.
You know how to cross the street.
넌 똑똑한 아이니까 길을 건널때는
이제 어떻게 해야 하는지 알거야
Are you mad at me?
저한테 화내시는거에요?
Listen to me.
아빠 말 들어보렴
No one is mad at you.
아무도 너한테 화내지 않아
And this wasn't your fault.
네가 잘못해서 이런것도 아니고 말야
I'm the one who should have been
looking out for you.
아빠가 널 보살펴 줬어야
했는데 그러지 못했구나
You weren't even there.
아빤 거기 없었잖아요
But I should have been.
그래도 그랬어야 했어
Hey, buddy, listen.
얘야
I got to go,
but I'll call you back later, okay?
끊어야겠구나
나중에 다시 전화하마
Okay. Bye.
알았어요
끊어요
Cameron?
캐머론?
I love you.
사랑한다, 얘야
Cam?
캐머론?
Yeah.
What have we got on Franklin?
그래, 프랭클린 소식 좀 있나?
Nothing new since
오늘 아침 이후로
this morning.
새로운건 없습니다만
Another witness from the Minnesota
diner robbery gave a positive I.D.
미네소타 식당 강도사건의 다른 목격자
로부터 확실하게 신원 확인을 받았습니다
Good. 'Cause I just landed in
Minneapolis 15 minutes ago.
미니애폴리스에 도착한지
15분밖에 안되었으니 잘됐군
- Anything else?
- 또 다른건?
- Yeah. The girl. Dede.
- 네, 그 여자애, 디디말입니다
Apparently, she's been ill,
some chronic condition.
아무래도 아픈것 같습니다
지병이 있는것 같아요
Fax Franklin's mug shot to every
hospital in southeastern Minnesota.
팩스로 프랭클린의 사진을 미네소타
남동부의 모든병원에 배포하도록 해
Already done.
벌써 조치했습니다
With any luck, she'll get sick
enough to need one,
잘하면 여자애가 병원치료를
요할만큼 악화될거고
then he'll show his face.
그럼 프랭클린이
모습을 드러내겠죠
You don't have kids, do you, Lang?
랭, 자넨 아이가 없지?
Nope.
네
Call me when you have
something else.
다른 사항 있으면 전화주게
I'll take that.
이거 주세요
- We didn't get it.
- What?
- 실패했어
- 뭐라고?
And we need to get back in there soon.
빨리 다시 들어가봐야해
Once the Company finds out
Sara was in there,
일단 "컴퍼니" 놈들이 새라가
클럽에 있었다는걸 알게되면
it won't be long before
they start wondering why.
뒤를 캐기 시작하는건 시간문제야
Find a spot close to
the club and sit tight.
클럽에서 가까운 곳에
자리잡고 기다려
We're going to take the car.
차를 타야 하니까 말야
- We'll be back in a couple of hours.
- Where you going?
- 몇시간안에 돌아올게
- 어디 가는건데?
Turns out that maybe there's one
member of the club who can help us.
클럽회원 중에 한명이
우릴 도와줄 수도 있을것 같아
Who?
누군데?
Pope?
포프?
Just a minute.
잠시만요
Henry.
소장님
What are you doing here?
여긴 어쩐 일이요?
Aside from jumping bail and
evading the authorities?
보석중에 달아난건 제쳐두고라도
당국의 추적까지 받고 있잖소?
There's something that you need to hear,
but, first, I need to know if you'll listen.
들으셔야 하는 말이 있는데
우선, 들어보실건지 알아야겠어요
I can assure you, Sara,
we've got nothing to discuss.
장담컨데, 새라
우린 이야기 할게 없소
Sir, please.
I need five minutes.
부탁이에요, 소장님
5분만 주세요
After that, if you want us to,
we'll leave.
그 후에도 똑같은 생각이시면
저흰 떠날게요
Who's "us"?
"저희" 라니?
도미닉 퍼셀
(링컨 버로우스 役)
웬트워스 밀러
(마이클 스코필드 役)
아마우리 노라스코
(페르난도 수크레 役)
웨이드 윌리엄스
(브래드 벨릭 役)
폴 에델스타인
(폴 켈러맨 요원 役)
로버트 니퍼
("티백" 테오도르 베그웰 役)
락먼드 던바
("씨노트" 벤자민 마일스 프랭클린 役)
새라 웨인 칼리스
(새라 텐크레디 役)
윌리엄 피크너
(알렉산더 머혼 요원 役)
Prison Break
2x17 "Bad Blood"
ORIGINAL AIR DATE ON FOX
2007/02/19
I don't want any trouble.
문제 일으키고 싶진 않아
Good. Because that's
not why we're here.
잘됐네요, 그것 때문에
여기 온건 아니니까요
What the hell are you thinking about?
대체 무슨 생각을 하고 있는거야?
Waltzing in here?
You're a wanted criminal!
여기서 왈츠라도 추려고?
자넨 수배된 범죄자라고!
In case you've forgotten,
혹시 잊었나본데
I dedicated my career,my entire life,
to keeping people like you behind bars.
난 자네같은 놈들을 투옥시키는데
내 경력과 전생애를 바쳐왔네
You're talking about guilty people.
My brother is innocent.
그건 죄를 범한 사람들 얘기지요
제 형은 결백합니다
And we may have the
evidence to prove it.
그 사실을 증명할 증거를
저희가 손에 얻은것 같습니다
Well, I don't care.
I want you out of here.
뭐, 내 알 바 아니니
여기서 나가주게
It's in a lockbox at the Corona del
Oro club, and you're a member.
그건 '코로나 델 오로' 클럽의 잠긴 상자
안에 들어있고 소장님은 그곳의 회원이시죠
Out!
나가게!
Henry, please listen.
소장님, 제발 들어보세요
Sara, I'm tempted to say.
You should have known better.
새라, 별로 말할 기분이 아니네
좀 더 현명히 생각했어야지
But after what you did..
자네가 그러고 난 후에..
My father was looking into the
Burrows case when he was murdered.
아버지는 살해 될 당시
버로우스 사건을 검토하고 계셨어요
This key is the only thing
I could recover from his body.
이 열쇠가 아버지의 몸에서 찾을 수
있었던 유일한 물건이고요
앨라배마 주(州)
코네큐 군(郡)
Where are we going?
어디 가는거에요?
They're hungry.
애들이 배 고플거에요
We've been driving all day.
하루종일 차만 타고 있었잖아요
Chick-O-Stick.
'Chick-O-Stick' 이라도 먹어
※ Chick-O-Stick - 초코바의 일종
They need real food.
밥을 먹어야죠
Soon enough, pumpkin.
다 와갑니다요, 마님
Alackaday..
아아..
Miscreants.
비열하고..
Defilers.
추악한..
Defacers.
파괴자들..
Despoilers.
약탈자들..
What is this?
이게 뭐에요?
My home.
내 고향집이야
멕시코, TECPATAN
익스타파로부터 35마일 외곽
어디까지 가요?
공항이요
운 좋으시구만
얼마나 걸리죠?
20분 정도?
비행기 타시려고요?
제 여자친구가
4시 비행기를 탈거거든요
문제없을거에요
잘됐네요
- 카데나다
- 어디쯤인가?
20마일 남았다
알았다
뭐하신거에요?
전 공항 안전 요원이거든요
미국 탈주범이
비행기를 탔다나 뭐라나
미네소타 주(州)
미니애폴리스
Okay.
자..
All right, sweetie,
why don't you sit over here, okay?
얘야, 여기 잠깐 앉아 있으렴
All right.
그렇지
I'm going to go over there
and I'm going to talk to the lady.
아빤 가서 저기 있는
언니랑 얘기 좀 하고올게
All right?
You need anything?
알았지?
뭐 필요한거 있니?
You sure?
정말?
Okay.
그래, 알았다
Yes. / Uh.. My daughter, Dede,
she's really sick.
네 / 어.. 제 딸 디디가 너무 아파서요
She's had this kidney thing
since she was real young.
아주 어릴때부터
신장(腎臟)이 안좋았거든요
- Where is she?
- She's sitting right there.
- 어디있죠?
- 저쪽에 앉아 있어요
- Have you been here before?
- No. I'm from out of town.
- 전에 오신적이 있으신가요?
- 아뇨, 타지(他地)사람입니다
Can I see your insurance card?
의료보험증 좀 보여주실까요?
Um... no, no.
I don't have any insurance.
어.. 아뇨
전 의료보험에 안들었습니다
After I left the army,
they discontinued my insurance..
군을 전역하고 나서
의료보험 신청을 안했거든요
Are you a resident of
Hennepin County?
헤네핀 군(郡) 거주자세요?
Like I said,
we're from out of town.
말씀드렸지만
이곳 사람이 아닙니다
You have a driver's license?
운전면허증은 있으세요?
Look, I don't have a driver's license,
an insurance card, or anything like that,
이봐요, 제가 운전면허증이나
의료보험증 같은 건 없지만
but I do know the law.
저도 법은 잘 알고 있어요
You have to see my little girl.
당신들은 내 딸을 진찰해야 해요
- Let me go get my supervisor.
- Good.
- 수간호사에게 말해 볼게요
- 좋아요
I don't give a rat's ass
about you or your brother.
난 자네 형제에겐
관심가지지 않을걸세
I trusted you, I took you under my wing,
I treated you like my own son.
난 자넬 신임했고
친아들처럼 여기며 보살펴줬었네
I believed you!
자넬 믿었었다고!
Day after day, you lied to me.
자넨 날이면 날마다
내게 거짓말을 했던거야
What kind of a man does that?
사람이 어찌 그럴 수 있나?
- A desperate one.
- Yeah.
- 어쩔 수 없었습니다
- 그래
Well..
You two made a big mistake
coming here today.
자넨 오늘 여길 오는 바람에
두가지 큰 실수를 한거네
You give me no choice.
자네가 어쩔 수 없는
선택을 하게 만들었어
I'm going to notify the
authorities right now.
지금 당장 당국에 신고할거야
I'm sorry..
죄송합니다만
but I can't let you do that.
그러시게 할 순 없습니다
I don't want to hurt you, Henry.
다치게 하고 싶진 않습니다, 소장님
Said by the man with the gun.
총들고 있던 놈들은
다들 그리 말했었지
If it's the only way
I can convince you, so be it.
만약 이게 소장님을 설득 할
유일한 방법이라면 쏠겁니다
Well, you're not going to
convince me by doing that.
글쎄, 자넨 그런식으로
날 설득하진 않을걸세
I'm not the man you think I am.
전 소장님이 생각하시는
그런 놈이 아닙니다
Yeah, well, I have a pretty good idea
who you are, Michael.
난 자네가 어떤 사람인지
아주 잘 알고있네, 마이클
If that's true, then you already know
I never wanted to be in Fox River.
그러시다면 제가 감옥에 가고 싶어서
간건 아니라는 것도 이미 아시겠군요
I never wanted to
meet you, Henry.
저도 소장님을
만나고 싶지 않았습니다
I certainly didn't want
to ruin your life.
소장님의 인생을 망치려던건
더더욱 아니었고요
Yeah. Well,
you've done a pretty damn good job.
그래, 아주 더럽게도 잘하셨구만
You're not saying anything to him
I haven't said myself, Henry.
제가 말씀드리지 않았던 말은
그에게 하지 마세요, 소장님
I've looked into this. What he's
saying to you is absolutely true.
저도 이 사건을 알아봤는데
마이클의 주장은 정말로 사실이에요
I just want my brother's life back.
전 단지 제 형의 삶을
되찾아주고 싶을 뿐입니다
I want people to know the truth.
I'd give anything for that.
사람들에게 진실을 밝히고 싶어요
그에 따른 댓가가 어떤것이든지요
I'd lay down my life.
전 제 인생을 포기했습니다
Well, that's easy for you to say,
standing on that side of the gun.
글쎄, 총을 겨누고 있는 사람이
무슨 말인들 못하겠나
What if I'm standing on this side?
이젠 어떠십니까?
There are places that can
better serve your needs.
따님을 진찰해 줄
보다 나은 곳이 있어요
Look, I know my rights, okay?
이봐요, 나도 내 권리
정도는 안다고요
This isn't a primary care facility.
여긴 초기 진료 시설이 아니에요
We provide necessary care
in life-threatening situations.
저흰 생명이 위급한 상황을 다루는데
필요한 시설만을 갖추고 있다고요
Look, I know what this is.
나도 여기가 어딘지 알아요
Are you going to wait until she's
dead before you give her some help?
저 애가 죽을때까지 기다렸다가
진료 해 줄 작정인거요?
Is that what you're telling me?!
그렇게 하겠다는겁니까?
I'm not going to
argue with you, sir.
말싸움 하자는게 아니에요, 선생님
This is a hospital,
not a homeless shelter.
여긴 병원이지 노숙자들의
임시 숙소가 아니라고요
A what?
뭐라고요?
What did you just say to me?
방금 뭐라고 했습니까?
I can't believe you people.
당신들 정말..
믿기지가 않는구만
Come on.
The line is a little bit too long, okay?
가자, 환자가 좀 많다는구나
We'll go somewhere else.
다른 곳으로 가야겠어
Where are we going?
어디로 가는건데?
We got to find another
doctor, sweetie.
다른 의사선생님을
찾아보자꾸나, 얘야
Oh my god.
이런, 맙소사
Let's go.
가자
Move!
비켜요!
Come on, baby.
얘야, 꽉 잡아
Franklin!
프랭클린!
Move out of the way!
좀 비켜주세요!
FBI! Stop!
FBI다! 멈춰라!
Stop!
멈춰!
Okay.
알았어요
Okay. Okay, okay.
알았어요, 알았어
Just one second, baby.
Baby, you got to get down, okay?
잠깐만, 얘야
잠깐 내려와봐, 알았지?
- No! No, sweetie, you got to get down.
- You got to let him go, honey.
- 아니, 아니, 얘야, 내려와봐
- 아빠 놔 주거라, 얘야
Get down. Get down.
내려와, 내려와
- Honey, you got to let him go.
- Come. / No.
- 착하지, 얘야, 내려오렴
- 어서 / 싫어
Man, she's not letting go.
이봐, 얘가 안놔주는데
Don't let her pay
for your mistakes.
네가 저지른 잘못의 댓가를
애가 치르게 하진마라
You hear me?
알아들었어?
I could shoot you right now
and not even think twice.
망설임없이 지금 당장
자넬 쏠 수도 있어
But you won't.
하지만 그러지 않으실거에요
You spent too much time around prisons
to throw your life away like that.
그렇게 일생을 내던져 버리기엔
교도소에서 종사하신 기간이 너무 길지요
What the hell are
you trying to pull?
도대체 무슨 꿍꿍이속이야?
It's simple-- that's the key
to an innocent man's freedom.
간단해요. 저게 바로 결백한
한 사람을 자유롭게 해 줄 열쇠지요
Come on, Henry.
생각해보세요, 소장님
We both know there's
something going on here.
우리 모두 이 사건에
뭔가가 있다는걸 알고 있잖아요
Too many people have died.
너무 많은 사람들이 죽어야 했어요
Look me in the eye,
제 눈을 똑바로 보시면서
tell me you don't believe there's
a cover-up going on right now.
은폐공작이 벌어지고 있다는 사실을
믿지 못하겠다고 말씀해 보세요
I've got no moral obligations
here, Michael.
이 사건에 대해 내가 가질
도덕적 의무는 없네, 마이클
As far as I know,
Lincoln is as guilty as hell.
내가 알고 있는 한 링컨은
아주 지독한 죄를 저질렀어
Then take a ten-minute drive with me,
and we'll find out.
그럼 차로 10분만 가셔서
저와 함께 알아보시죠
That's all I ask.
이게 제가 드리는 부탁입니다
Henry, you've looked into this before.
You've thought about it.
소장님도 전에 이 사건을 검토하시고
생각도 해 보셨잖아요
I have.
그랬었지
And I've come to
one conclusion.
그리곤 한가지 결론을 내렸었지
this has nothing to do with me.
이 사건에 있어
내가 할 수 있는건 없다고 말야
But I am a man of the law,
하지만 난 법을 집행하는 사람이고
and right now, I've got a convicted felon
standing inside my house.
지금 내 집 안에는 중죄를 저지른
죄수가 들어와 있단 말일세
Well, maybe there's something I can
offer you to make you change your mind.
그러시다면 마음을 바꾸실만한
제안을 할 수도 있을 것 같습니다
What do you intend
to do with us?
우리랑 뭘 할 생각인거에요?
You grease monkey.
넌 정비사야, 임마
You don't deserve minimum wage.
최저 임금도 받지 못하면서 무슨..
The hell I don't,
working graveyard.
젠장, 당연하지
고물상에서 일하는 주제에
There ain't no man deserve more pennies
on a dollar per hour than they got IQ points in their head.
누가 네 I.Q보다 더 많은
시간 당 1달러 이상을 주겠냐, 임마
I ain't stupid.
내가 바보냐?
Seems equal stupid
as the rest of you.
너만큼 멍청해 보이는
놈들이 있구만 뭘
Seems to run in the genes.
유전자가 똑같으니
뭐 별 수 있겠어?
Teddy!
테디!
Ten symonyms!
동의어(同義語) 10개 대기다!
Pick a word.
단어 대 봐
단어 대 보라고
Destroy.
Destroy
(파괴하다/박멸시키다/무효로하다 등)
Ten synonyms for "destroy."
"Destroy"의 동의어 10개..
Annul.
Mutilate.
Liquidate. Abrogate.
Quell. Ravage.
Expunge. Demolish.
Extirpate. Extinguish.
Whoo, you see that?!
와우! 저것봐라?
Stupid, my pail,
my boy's gonna be president.
멍청한 놈같으니
내 아들은 대통령감이라구
How come you ain't studying?
왜 공부하지 않는거냐?
'Cause I'm tired.
피곤하기도 하고
'Cause I feel like
a circus freak.
무슨 서커스단 같이
별난 놈처럼 보여서요
Well..
그래, 뭐..
now..
자..
It's in your own best interest.
네가 가장 재미있어 하는거잖아
Don't you understand that? Hmm?
그걸 모르겠니? 응?
Now, you're going to
be president someday.
넌 언젠간 대통령이 될거야
You mark my words.
아빠 말 잊지 마라
Theodore.
테오도르
Theodore, do you hear me?
테오도르, 내 말 듣는거에요?
What are you going
to do with us?
우리랑 대체 뭘하려는 거에요?
We're gonna put down some roots.
어딘가엔 자리를 잡아야지
You wanted me dead, Paul.
넌 날 죽이려고 했었어, 폴
Just following orders.
명령에 따른 것 뿐이야
Sent me to the chair for
something I didn't do,
그 대통령이란 사람을 위해
하지도 않은 죄를 뒤집어 씌우고
all for your president.
You were willing to do that.
전기의자에 앉혔던거야
넌 기꺼이 그리했고 말이지
Just.. following.. orders.
명령에 따랐을 뿐이라고
Steadman said you loved her.
네가 그녀를 사랑했었다고
스테드먼이 그랬잖아
Steadman was a deranged man
that lived in a locked box.
스테드먼은 짜맞춘 틀 안에 살았던
제정신이 아닌 놈이었을 뿐야
You don't love someone that
loves power more than life.
넌 생명보다 권력을 중요시
하는 사람을 사랑하진 않잖아?
Bitter, huh?
쓰라리겠구만
Am I?
그럴까?
No offense, but
기분나쁘게 들릴진 모르겠지만
you're not capable of
understanding the relationship.
넌 '관계' 라는 걸 이해하는데엔
그다지 소질이 없는 것 같아
Okay, any way you look at it,
좋아, 네가 이 상황을
어떻게 보는지 간에
there is no light
at the end of this tunnel.
이 수렁에서
빠져 나올 희망은 없어
One way or another,
you and I, we die.
어떻게 해서든 너와 나
우린 모두 죽게 돼있어
Your brother, too.
네 동생도 마찬가지고
Which is a shame given
all he's done for you.
마이클이 한 모든 행동으로 인해
망신을 당하게 된 셈이지
I have a sister
I haven't talked to in 15 years.
내겐 15년동안 말 한마디
못해본 여동생이 있지
Think she's better off for it?
걔가 더 틀린거라 생각해?
We'll make it.
우린 해낼거야
- What is that, faith?
- Yeah, that's faith.
대체 뭘 믿고 그러는거야?
믿음? / 그래, 믿음이지
All I see is a black hole.
내 눈엔 블랙홀만이 보여
And sooner or later,
조만간에
they are going to
suck each one of us into it.
놈들은 우리들 하나 하나를
그 안으로 빨아 들일거야
But when they come for me,
하지만 내 차례가 오게 되면
I'm going to take
as many of them with me as I can.
내가 할 수 있는 만큼
놈들을 끌고 들어갈거야
She must have really
broken your heart, Paul.
정말로 많이
상심했나보구나, 폴
President Reynolds attended
a Chicago fundraiser last night
레이놀드 대통령은 어젯밤
이틀간의 방문 계획으로
as part of her two-day stop
in the Windy City.
시카고에서 열린
모금 행사에 참석했습니다
Reynolds' popularity continues to soar
in the Midwest with appearances scheduled
주말까지 미시간 주(州)의 인디애나폴리스,
디트로이트, 플린트 시(市)등을 방문 할 예정인 가운데
in Indianapolis, Detroit and Flint,
Michigan later in the week.
중서부 지역에서의 대통령 지지율은
여전히 상승 중 인것으로 나타났습니다
Mr. Kim.
요원님
Sarah Tancredi
surfaced in Chicago.
새라 텐크레디가
시카고에 나타났습니다
She was spotted at the Corona
de Oro Club about an hour ago.
'코로나 데 오로 클럽'에서
약 1시간 전에 목격되었습니다
- Corona de Oro Club?
- It's a cigar club.
- 코로나 데 오로 클럽?
- 시가 클럽인데
Her father was a member.
그녀의 아버지가 회원이었으며
He kept a private
humidor there.
그곳에 개인물품을 보관하는
장소를 가지고 있었답니다
Get me a jet to Chicago.
시카고로 갈 제트기 준비시켜
도착했군요
그만 헤어지죠
터미널은 이쪽이에요
네, 어..
화장실 좀 가야겠는데요
터미널 안에 하나 있어요
정말 고마워요
태워주셔서 감사합니다
무기 휴대하고 있지?
아마 필요할거야
이 놈을 잡아야 하니까
여기있어!
Tell me you're not still
thinking he's going to show.
아직도 수크레가 오길
기다리는거니?
He's let you down so many times.
You know that.
한두번 실망시킨게 아니란거
너도 잘 알잖아
Maybe it's the baby in me
that's telling me that
내가 아이를 가졌다는걸
알고 있는 이상
this time it's going to be different.
이번엔 다를거라 생각해
I don't mean to burst your bubble,
but he's not going to show.
네 희망을 깨고 싶진 않지만
수크레는 나타나지 않을거야
Bubble's not burst.
역시 내 생각이 맞았어
- I got three words for you.
- Yeah?
- 딱 한마디만 할게
- 응?
We gotta run.
도망가야 해
Good seeing you, Theresa!
만나서 반가웠어요, 테레사!
- I'm so glad you came.
- You're crazy.
- 와 줘서 고마워
- 자긴 미쳤어 정말
How did they know?
놈들이 어떻게 알았지?
You're certain..
자네 정말..
about what's in the box?
상자 안에 뭐가 들었는지 확신하나?
No, but it's all we've got.
아뇨, 하지만 저희에겐 이것뿐입니다
Thank you, Henry.
고마워요, 소장님
You sure about this?
확신하는거에요?
No.
아뇨
Either way,
you still owe me dinner.
어떻든간에
나한테 저녁은 사야해요
Is that so?
그런가요?
Yeah.
그럼요
First week in Fox River, you promised me,
if you ever got out of there, you'd take me to dinner.
폭스리버에 온 첫 주에 밖에 나가기만 하면
저녁 사준다고 약속했었잖아요
Well, maybe,
after we wrap this up,
이 일만 잘 해결된다면
we can stop off and get you a burrito
on the way back to Pope's house.
소장님의 집으로 돌아가는 길에
'부리토' 를 먹으러 들르죠 뭐
※ Burrito - 멕시코 요리의 일종
Scofield, I don't know
what you're used to,
스코필드, 그간 뭘
즐겨먹었는진 모르겠지만
but anything short of a filet mignon
is not going to cut it with me.
저는 '필레미뇽' 같은 걸
칼질 하는걸론 부족해요
※ Filet Mignon - 두껍게 자른 안심 스테이크
It's a date.
그냥 데이트잖아요
Give me the phone.
전화기 줘 봐
- Hey.
- 말해
- How did you pull that off?
- 무슨 꿍꿍이야?
I'll tell you later.
나중에 얘기 해 줄게
Is he in yet?
아직 안들어갔어?
Yep.
방금 들어갔어
This shouldn't take more than
a couple of minutes.
이건 몇 분밖에 안걸리는 일이야
Any longer than that,
we'll know we've got trouble.
더 오래걸리면
문제가 생겼다고 생각하면 돼
- Mr. Pope. This way.
- Thank you.
어서오세요, 포프 씨
이쪽입니다 / 고맙소
Hey, Warren.
How's it going?
오랜만이시군요, 소장님
어떻게 지내십니까?
Did you hear
what happened this morning?
오늘 아침에 무슨일이
있었는지 들으셨습니까?
- Sara Tancredi came in.
- Yeah. So I heard.
- 새라 텐크레디가 왔었습니다
- 그래, 나도 들었습니다
Next time,
don't let her get away. Thanks.
다음엔 놓치지 말아요
고맙습니다
Excuse me, do you mind if I borrow
your computer for a moment?
실례지만, 노트북 좀
잠시 빌려도 되겠습니까?
- No problem.
- Thanks.
- 물론입니다
- 고맙습니다
Pitch in, childrens!
좀 도와줘, 얘들아
We can't do this.
그럴 순 없어요
We can't live here.
여기서 살 순 없다고요
No, of course not like this.
We gonna clean.
이 상태론 당연하지
우리가 치울거야
We are cleaning!
We gonna rebuild!
우리가 치우는거야!
우리가 재건하는거라고!
You can't do this to them.
Look at them.
애들 앞에서 이러면 안돼요
한번 보라고요
Y'all mind coming along
here for a minute.
잠깐 이리 와 보거라
Come on. I think we're past me waving
that gun around, don't you think?
이리 와, 총들고 설쳤던
일은 개의치 말고, 알았지?
What are you doing?
뭐 하는 거에요?
Nothing is gonna happen to them.
Susan. Susie Q.
애들은 아무 일 없을거야, 수잔
Do you think
I'd bring you here
이곳은 나에게
아주 성스러운 장소인데
to so sacred a place to me as this
if I meant you ill?
당신을 불쾌하게 만들려고
데려온거라 생각해?
Look at me!
날 봐!
I am not the animal you think
you see before you.
난 전에 당신이 보고 생각했던
짐승같은 놈이 아니야
I am the laws of karma
all come down wrong.
'카르마(業)의 법칙' 에 의하면
모든게 결정을 잘못했기 때문이지
※The law of karma - 카르마(업,業)의 법칙
Don't you understand?
내 말 이해하겠어?
I don't.
무슨 말인지 모르겠어요
What I'm trying to say is that..
그러니까 내가 하려는 말은..
I am the sin of my father.
내가 아버지의 업보를
졌다는 얘기야
Why are you telling me this?
왜 내게 이런 말을 하는건데요?
Because I love you.
당신을 사랑하니까
Because I want you
to understand me.
당신이 날 이해해 줬으면 하니까
I am the last
in the line of Bagwells.
난 백웰 가(家)의 일부 중
최후의 한 사람이야
The tail end of a corrupted breed.
타락한 생식(生殖)의 결과물이지
The earth, thank God,
shall see no more of our generations.
감사하게도 더이상 우리 세대는
지구상에서 볼 수 없게 될거야
I cannot procreate, Susan.
내 피를 물려받은 아이를
낳을 순 없어, 수잔
And yet, there's something in that
that gives me great hope.
그런데도 나에게
엄청난 희망을 준 게 있지
No more Bagwells shall
roam this planet.
더이상 이 땅에서 백웰 가(家)의
자손이 돌아다니는 일은 없어
Not with that vile blood in their veins.
그들의 혈관 속에
그 더러운 피가 흐르진 않을거야
All I want to do is
end the bloodline, extirpate it,
오로지 내가 원하는건
혈통을 끊어 집안을 멸(滅)하고
and start another, afresh.
새롭게 출발하는거야
- A new family.
- Oh, Teddy.
- 새로운 가족으로 말야
- 오, 테디
Those children are my salvation,
저 아이들이
이 세상을 더 좋은곳으로
my chance to make
this world a better place.
만들 기회를 준 나의 구원자야
I will be good, Susan.
착하게 살거야, 수잔
I will love them.
I will love you.
아이들을 사랑 할 거고
당신도 사랑 할 거야
I will take communion,
be baptized under a truer light.
성찬식에도 참석해서
진실을 빛 아래에서 세례도 받을게
All I ask is that you love me back,
당신이 날 다시 사랑 해주는게
내가 바라는 전부야
just a little.
단지 그것 뿐이야
Or learn to do so in time.
아니면 조만간 그리 되거나..
Can you do that, Susan?
그리 해줄 수 있는거지, 수잔?
I can't.
그럴 순 없어요
못하겠어요
I'm sorry.
미안해요
Teddy.
테디
Teddy. Please..
테디, 제발요
Teddy, I'm sorry.
미안해요, 테디
Where are we?
여긴 어디야?
At the doctor's office, sweetie.
진료실이란다, 얘야
Hello.
계세요?
Hello,
I have an emergency in here.
여보세요, 여기 급한 환자가 있어요
Hello?
선생님?
Hello.
저기요
Hey, you the doctor?
의사 선생님이십니까?
- Need to wait your turn.
- No, it is my turn.
- 차례를 기다려요
- 지금이 제 차례에요
This is an emergency right here.
급한 환자라고요
I need you to look at my daughter, okay?
She's not feeling too good.
제 딸 좀 봐주세요, 네?
너무 아프단 말이에요
Please.
부탁입니다
Sweetie, hold on.
꽉 잡아라, 얘야
All right, look, this is all the
money I got, okay? That's $400.
이봐요, 이게 제가 가진 돈 전부에요
400달러 입니다
Please look at my daughter.
제발 딸아이 좀 봐주세요
What's the matter with her?
어디가 아프길래 그래요?
She has a kidney disease-- PKD.
신장병이 있습니다
다낭성신질환 이에요
※PKD(polycystic kidney disease)
- 다낭성신질환 / 다낭종신
Normally, we have it under control, but
I don't like what I'm seeing right now.
평소엔 대수롭지 않게 넘어갔는데
지금은 도저히 못보고 있겠어요
she's happened stomach hurts, okay?
And she's always hot.
배가 아프고 항상 열이 많이 나요
- How's her appetite?
- It's gone.
- 식욕은 어떤가요?
- 떨어진지 오래에요
She's always tired,
ain't that right, baby?
항상 피곤해 하고요
그렇지, 얘야?
All right.
알겠습니다
Hop up here.
여기 눕히세요
Thank you.
감사합니다
He just wants to take
a good look at you, okay?
의사선생님이 이제 안아프게
해 주실거란다, 알겠지?
May need to run a few tests.
테스트를 몇가지
해 봐야겠습니다만
Just do what you have to do, man.
필요한 건 뭐든지 하세요, 선생님
I'm gonna be right here,
okay, baby?
아빠가 옆에 있어줄게
알았지, 얘야?
Okay.
그래
- Yeah.
- 그래
- What's going on now?
- 지금은 어때?
Still in there.
아직 안에 있어
This is taking too long.
너무 오래 걸리는데
Wait, wait, wait.
Here he comes.
잠깐, 잠깐
지금 나온다
- What's happening?
- We got company.
- 무슨일이야?
- 불청객이 있어
Hello, Henry.
안녕하십니까, 헨리
I didn't know
you were a cigar man.
시가를 즐기시는지는 몰랐네요
Who are you?
누구십니까?
Uh, a friend. A colleague,
음.. 친구라고 해야하나..
동료라고 하는게 좋겠네요
in fact,
We're both in law enforcement.
사실 둘 다
법을 집행하는 사람이니까요
I'm not anymore.
난 더이상 아닙니다만
That's right.
You're, uh.. retired.
아, 그렇지
은퇴하셨지요?
- Know the guy?
- Yeah.
- 아는 놈이야?
- 그래
Looks like the lifestyle's
treating you well.
평온한 은퇴 후 생활을
보내시는 것 같군요
Socializing over
Cubans and cognac?
쿠바 산 시가와 코냑이랑
사귀시기라도 하시는겁니까?
But that's not
what you were doing, is it?
하지만 그것 때문에
여기 오신건 아니죠, 안그렇습니까?
Henry.
헨리
You don't mind
if ask you to empty your pockets?
소지품을 좀 검사해도
괜찮으시겠지요?
- As a matter of fact, I do.
- I'm not going to play any games with you.
- 물론 안되겠소만
- 당신하고 장난치는 거 아닙니다
We both know
why you came here today.
오늘 이곳에 왜 왔는지
우리 둘다 잘 알잖아요
I suggest you get out of my way,
young man.
내 앞에서 비키게나, 젊은이
I can't do that.
그렇겐 못하겠는데요
Unless you'd like to cause serious
trouble for yourself and your family,
당신과 당신 가족에게 심각한 문제가
생기길 바라는게 아니라면
I advise you to hand over
whatever it is you found.
찾아낸게 뭐든 간에
우리에게 넘기라고 말하고 싶군요
Now.
지금 당장 말이오
Michael?
마이클?
Get in!
타세요!
Let's go!
가자!
Linc!
형!
Sara!
새라!
It's okay, it's okay.
Easy, easy, it's okay, it's okay.
괜찮아요, 괜찮아요
괜찮으니 진정하세요
Ma'am, are you all right?
괜찮으십니까, 부인?
- I don't understand.
- We got a call.
- 어떻게 된건지 모르겠네요
- 제보를 받았습니다
Someone said
there's a hostage situation here.
누군가가 여기서
인질극이 벌어졌다고 하더군요
No one knew we were here.
우리가 여기 있단 걸
아는 사람이 없었는데요
Are you okay?
Okay.
괜찮니?
다행이구나
Hey, so what's going on?
그래, 어떻습니까?
I'm afraid your daughter
shows signs of renal failure.
유감이지만 따님에게
신장 질환의 징후가 보입니다
She ever had hemodialysis?
혹시 혈액 투석을
한 적이 있습니까?
No, hemo.. No.
No, this has never really gone that far.
아뇨, 혈액.. 아니에요
그렇게까지 악화되진 않았을겁니다
What, are you planning
on doing it right here?
뭐에요, 지금 여기서
혈액 투석을 하려고요?
We're not set up for it.
여긴 그런 시술을
할 만한 시설이 없습니다
And neither is she.
따님도 마찬가지고요
But there is a county dialysis clinic
a few blocks away.
몇 블럭 떨어진 곳에 군(郡)에서 운영하는
투석 요법 클리닉이 있습니다만
But we're gonna have to place
a catheter in her neck
그 전에 따님의 목에
카테터를 삽입해야만
※Catheter(카테터)
- 요도/혈관 등에 삽입하는 도관(導管)
so she can be examined.
검사를 받을 수 있을 겁니다
※Catheter(카테터)
- 요도/혈관 등에 삽입하는 도관(導管)
Hold on, sweetie,
this is gonna be a little cold.
얘야, 잠깐만
조금 차가울거다
It's okay, baby.
괜찮아, 얘야
Whoa, whoa, wait, wait, wait.
Wait, what, what is that?
워 워.. 잠깐만, 잠깐만요
뭐에요 그건?
It's a trocar.
It's used for placing the catheter.
투관침(套管針) 입니다
카테터에 붙여 사용하는거죠
- Do we really have to go this far?
- Look.
- 정말 이렇게까지 해야 하는겁니까?
- 이봐요
I'm doing the best I can here,
but you got to understand something.
여기서 할 수 있는 최대한의 조치를
하고 있지만 이해하셔야 할 점이 있습니다
Your daughter is sick.
따님은 아픈 상태이고
Now, this may look like
a desperate measure because it is.
이 방법이 필사적인 조치라고
말씀드릴 수 있겠네요
This is gonna hurt
a little bit, sweetie.
조금 아플거란다, 얘야
Stop!
Stop.
멈춰요!
그만해요
Come on, baby.
이리오렴
Come with me.
I can't do this.
가자꾸나
이렇게 할 순 없어
What's going on?
무슨일이야?
I made a deal with Pope.
포프와 거래를 했어
You made a deal with Pope?
What kind of deal?
포프와 거래를 했다고?
무슨 거래를?
If he came with us and
if we got what we needed,
우리와 같이 가서
우리가 원하는 걸 가져다 주면
I said I'd turn myself in.
자수하겠다고 했어
What?!
뭐라고?!
We don't even know
what this thing is!
우리 아직 이게 뭔지도 모르잖아!
It could be nothing, Michael.
아무것도 아닐 수도 있다고, 마이클!
- You know about this?
- Not until it came out of his mouth.
- 당신도 알고 있었어요?
- 말하기 전까진 몰랐어요
It's the only thing
I could think of.
내가 생각 해낼 수 있는
유일한 방법이었어
You two can still finish this.
형이나 새라는
아직 마무리 할 수 있잖아
You'll just have to do it without me.
이젠 나없이 해야만 할거야
I'm not gonna let
you do this, Michael.
그리하게 놔두지 않을거야, 마이클
There's no coming back from this!
이런다고 돌아오는건 없다고!
- Hold on.
- What's the holdup?
- 잠깐
- 뭐가 잠깐이라는 거에요?
Your brother's right.
형 말이 맞네
I wouldn't count on the courts to show
you any leniency in this.
이 일에 조금의 관용을 베풀어
자넬 법정에 맡기진 않겠네
That doesn't matter.
그건 문제가 안됩니다
I said I'd hold up my end of the deal.
거래 조건은 지킨다고 말씀드렸잖아요
You already did.
이미 지켰네
I listened to this.
이걸 들어봤다네
You have something here.
뭔가 들어있더구만
There's gonna be a lot of people
who wish you didn't, but you do.
많은 사람들이 원했지만 하지 못했던,
하지만 자네는 해낸 것이 들어있다네
Listen, Henry..
저기요, 소장님..
I'd go now if I were you.
내가 자네였으면
당장 떠났을거야
And don't consider
this forgiveness.
그리고 이걸 용서라고
생각하지도 않을거네
In fact, I'm about ten seconds away
from changing my mind.
사실, 10초 정도면
내 마음이 바뀔수도 있어
Thank you.
감사합니다
Okay..
좋아..
Here, listen..
자.. 들어보렴
Let's tuck in your head, all right?
Okay?
머리 집어넣자, 괜찮지?
Come on. Let's go.
자, 이제 가자
Let's just..
Let's just sit for a bit longer, okay?
그냥..
그냥 좀 더 앉아 있자, 알았지?
We're gonna go in a little bit, okay?
조금만 더 있다 가자, 알았지?
You know Daddy loves you
with all his heart, right?
아빠가 온 마음을
다 바쳐 사랑하는거 알지?
I love you so much.
정말 사랑한다
I'm so sorry.
정말 미안하다
I'm so sorry, baby.
정말 미안하다, 얘야
- Yeah.
- 그래
- Got a call for you.
- 전화가 와 있습니다
I'll call back.
I just heard from some clinic up north.
내가 다시 전화하지. 방금 북쪽에
있는 진료소에서 연락을 받았거든
They had contact with
Franklin a half an hour ago.
1시간 전쯤에
프랭클린과 접촉했다는군
I think you want to take this.
이 전화를 받으셔야 할겁니다
Put it through.
연결하게
Yeah? Mahone.
네, 머혼입니다
- Is this the man in charge?
- 담당자 되십니까?
- Oh, yeah.
- 맞습니다
My name..
전..
is Benjamin Miles Franklin.
벤자민 마일스 프랭클린이고
And I want to turn myself in.
자수하려고 합니다만
But I got one condition.
한가지 조건이 있습니다
My wife, she goes free.
내 아내를 석방 해주시오
My little daughter,
she needs her mother.
내 어린 딸아인
엄마가 필요합니다
I don't think I need to make
a deal with you, Mr. Franklin.
내가 당신과 거래할 이유는
없다고 봅니다만, 프랭클린씨
And what if
I got something you need?
내게 당신에게 필요한
정보가 있다면 어떻습니까?
Your wife was released an hour ago.
She'll be here soon.
당신 아내는 1시간 전에 풀려났소
곧 여기로 올거요
You promise me that
she will be okay.
딸아이는 괜찮을거라 약속하시오
Just hold up
your end of the deal.
거래조건이나 지키시오
I will.
그럴거요
I'll get you Scofield.
스코필드를 잡게 해 드리겠소
자막배포 - 네이트 드라마 24 자유제작
(http://club.nate.com/24)
자유배포 / 수정금지
배포시 제작자 정보를 꼭 밝혀주세요
Here we go.
자, 시작해요
You think it's a conversation?
대화 내용인 것 같나요?
One they don't want us to hear.
우리가 듣지 않았으면
하는 대화겠지요
You ready?
준비됐어?
Let's do it.
틀어봐